{
  "assignments": [
    {
      "title": "Microsoft Fabric xxx",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "You have access to a historical dataset that contains the monthly expenses of the marketing department. You want to generate predictions of the expenses for the coming month. What task do you need to perform to predict the expenses for the coming month?",
          "options": ["Classification", "Regression", "Forecasting"],
          "answer": "Forecasting"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which feature in Microsoft Fabric should you use to review the results of MLflow's tracking through a user interface?",
          "options": ["Notebooks", "Experiments", "Models"],
          "answer": "Experiments"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which feature in Microsoft Fabric should you use to accelerate data exploration and cleansing?",
          "options": ["Dataflows", "Data Wrangler", "Lakehouse"],
          "answer": "Data Wrangler"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Administer a Microsoft Fabric environment ",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which of the following statements best describes the concept of capacity in Fabric?",
          "options": [
            "Capacity refers to a dedicated space for organizations to create, store, and manage Fabric items.",
            "Capacity defines the ability of a resource to perform an activity or to produce output.",
            "Capacity is a collection of items that are logically grouped together."
          ],
          "answer": "Capacity defines the ability of a resource to perform an activity or to produce output."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following statements is true about the difference between promotion and certification in Fabric?",
          "options": [
            "Promotion and certification both allow any workspace member to endorse content.",
            "Promotion requires a higher level of permissions than certification.",
            "Certification must be enabled in the tenant by the admin, while promotion can be done by a workspace member."
          ],
          "answer": "Certification must be enabled in the tenant by the admin, while promotion can be done by a workspace member."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Microsoft Fabric - Data Ingestion & Warehouse Quiz",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What are the four data ingestion options available in Microsoft Fabric for loading data into a data warehouse?",
          "options": [
            "COPY (Transact-SQL) statement, data pipelines, dataflows, and cross-warehouse.",
            "COPY (Transact-SQL) statement, data pipelines, dataflows, and Data Wrangler.",
            "COPY (Transact-SQL) statement, data pipelines, dataflows, and cross-platform ingestion."
          ],
          "answer": "COPY (Transact-SQL) statement, data pipelines, dataflows, and cross-warehouse."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the supported data sources and file formats for the COPY (Transact-SQL) statement in Warehouse?",
          "options": [
            "Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS) Gen2 and Azure Blob Storage, with PARQUET and CSV file formats.",
            "Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS) Gen1 and Azure Blob Storage, with PARQUET and CSV file formats.",
            "Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS) Gen2 and Azure Blob Storage, with ORC and CSV file formats."
          ],
          "answer": "Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS) Gen2 and Azure Blob Storage, with PARQUET and CSV file formats."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the recommended minimum file size when working with external data on files in Microsoft Fabric?",
          "options": ["At least 4 MB.", "At least 1 MB.", "At least 10 MB."],
          "answer": "At least 4 MB."
        }
      ]
    },

    {
      "title": "Microsoft Fabric - Data Warehousing Basics",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the primary language used for querying a data warehouse?",
          "options": ["Python", "SQL", "C#"],
          "answer": "SQL"
        },
        {
          "question": "Why is indexing important in a data warehouse?",
          "options": [
            "It makes the data warehouse look more organized.",
            "It speeds up data retrieval times.",
            "It helps in cleaning the data."
          ],
          "answer": "It speeds up data retrieval times."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the purpose of a fact table in a data warehouse?",
          "options": [
            "To store raw data.",
            "To store the results of calculations.",
            "To store metadata."
          ],
          "answer": "To store the results of calculations."
        }
      ]
    },

    {
      "title": "Microsoft Fabric - Monitoring & Performance",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "You want to monitor capacity unit consumption in your Fabric data warehouse. What tools should you use?",
          "options": [
            "Microsoft Azure Monitor",
            "Microsoft Fabric Capacity Metrics app",
            "Microsoft Azure Data Studio."
          ],
          "answer": "Microsoft Fabric Capacity Metrics app"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which dynamic management view provides details about SQL commands running in the data warehouse?",
          "options": [
            "sys.dm_exec_requests",
            "sys.dm_exec_connections",
            "sys.dm_exec_sessions"
          ],
          "answer": "sys.dm_exec_requests"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which view should you use to identify commonly run commands in your data warehouse?",
          "options": [
            "queryinsights.exec_requests_history",
            "queryinsights.long_running_queries",
            "queryinsights.frequently_run_queries"
          ],
          "answer": "queryinsights.frequently_run_queries"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Microsoft Fabric Basics",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the primary purpose of Microsoft Fabric?",
          "options": ["Design", "Data integration", "Gaming"],
          "answer": "Data integration"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which component helps in creating reports?",
          "options": ["Power BI", "Azure DevOps", "Excel"],
          "answer": "Power BI"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Advanced ML with Fabric",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which feature in Microsoft Fabric should you use to review the results of MLflow's tracking?",
          "options": ["Experiments", "Notebooks", "Dataflows"],
          "answer": "Experiments"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which Fabric tool accelerates data exploration?",
          "options": ["Data Wrangler", "Lakehouse", "Spark"],
          "answer": "Data Wrangler"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
